Guide to the Washington State Association of the U.A. Plumbers and Pipefitters Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- SERIES X: JURISDICTIONAL DOCUMENTS, 1945-1983; 1996-1997, 1941-1983; 1996-1997 (Box-folder 2/15; 5/9-5/29)
  Subseries X includes files pertaining to a variety of projects involving jurisdictional issues. Disagreements come to a head in Subseries C: Jurisdictional Disputes.
  The Series is subdivided by material format: Subseries A: Project Files; Subseries B: Jurisdictional Correspondence; Subseries C: Jurisdictional Disputes; Subseries D: Inter Agreements / Letters of Assent. Subseries A: Project Files is further subdivided by material function: Part A: Pre-Job and Mark-Up Meetings; Part B: Project Processes; Part C: Engineering Plans. Within each part, Individual files are arranged chronologically. Subseries B: Jurisdictional Correspondence is arranged chronologically. Subseries C: Jurisdictional Disputes is further subdivided by the arena in which the cases were settled: Part A: Impartial Jurisdictional Disputes Board for the Construction Industry; Part B: National Labor Relations Board. Individual files within each part are arranged chronologically.
  - Subseries A: Project Files, 1970-1984; 1996-1997 (Box-folder 1/30; 5/9-5/14; 5/16; 5/18-5/19; 5/21; 5/24)
    - Part 1: Pre-Job and Mark-Up Meetings, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 5/10-5/13; 5/16; 5/18-5/19; 5/21)
      - Washington Public Power Supply System No. 3 and No. 5, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 5/10; 5/19)
        - Pre-Job and Mark-Up Meeting - Washington Public Power Supply System No.3 and No. 5, 1980 (Box-folder 5/10)
        - Pre Job Meeting - M-K/ESI/LORD, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 5/19)
      - Pre-Job Meeting - Mayfield Unit #4 General Construction, 1980 (Box-folder 5/11)
      - Mark-Up Meeting - Hooker Chemical, 1980 (Box-folder 5/12)
      - Pre-Job Meeting - Puget Sound Power & Light - Gas Turbine Installation, Undated (Box-folder 5/13)
      - No. 12 Paper Machine Project - Cives Construction Co. - Equipment Jurisdictional Mark-Up, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 5/16)
    - Part 2: Project Processes 1970-1983; 1996-1997, 1970-1984; 1996-1997 (Box-folder 1/30; 5/9; 5/14; 5/18; 5/21; 5/24)
      - Wright Schuchart Harbor Co. - ARCO Project, 1970-1981 (Box-folder 5/14; 5/21)
        - Wright Schuchart Harbor Co. - ARCO Project, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 5/14)
        - Wright Schuchart Harbor Co. - ARCO Project, 1970-1978 (Box-folder 5/21)
      - Centralia Steam Plant - J. A. Kelly, 1974-1983 (Box-folder 5/18)
      - Setting Air Intake Filer - Satsop, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 5/24)
      - Waste Water Treatment Plant Piping, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 5/9)
      - Suggested Journal Article for Peter Kiewit Sons' Co Satsop Project, 1981 (Box-folder 1/30)
    - Part 3: Engineering Plans, 1974-1978 (Folder:oversize Map case drawer 21, Folder 7)
      - Engineering Plans - Wright Schuchart Harbor Co. - ARCO Project, 1974; 1 item (Folder:oversize Map case drawer 21, Folder 7)
      - Engineering Plans - Scott Paper Company Northwest Operations, 1974-1975; 13 items (Folder:oversize Map case drawer 21, Folder 7)
      - Engineering Plans - Grays Harbor Vanillin Plant, 1978; 2 items (Folder:oversize Map case drawer 21, Folder 7)
  - Subseries B: Jurisdictional Correspondence, 1945-1984 (Box-folder 2/15; 5/17; 5/20; 5/25)
    - Local 820 Requests for Grant County Jurisdiction and UA Denial Letter, 1945-1960 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Miscellaneous Jurisdictional Correspondence, 1961-1969 (Box-folder 5/25)
    - Miscellaneous Jurisdictional Correspondence, 1968-1984 (Box-folder 5/17)
    - Miscellaneous Project Correspondence, 1971-1979 (Box-folder 5/20)
  - Subseries C: Jurisdictional Disputes, 1948-1983 (Box-folder 5/15; 5/22; 5/26-5/29)
    - Part 1: Impartial Jurisdictional Disputes Board for the Construction Industry, 1948-1983 (Box-folder 5/15; 5/22; 5/27; 5/29)
      - International Hod Carriers, Building and Common Laborers Union - Jurisdictional Disputes, 1948-1980 (Box-folder 5/27)
      - National Joint Board for Settlement of Jurisdictional Disputes - Building and Construction Industry, 1950-1959 (Box-folder 5/29)
      - Impartial Jurisdictional Disputes Board for the Construction Industry, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 5/22)
      - Impartial Jurisdictional Disputes Board for the Construction Industry, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 5/15)
    - Part 2: National Labor Relations Board, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 5/26; 5/28)
      - UA Local No. 598 (Kennewick) and J. A. Jones Construction Company - NLRB Case No. 19-CD-54, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 5/28)
      - Sheet Metal Workers Union Local No. 150 and Stoker Engineering Company - NLRB Case No. 19-RC-2511, 1960- (Box-folder 5/26)
  - Subseries D: Inter Agreements / Letters of Interest, 1971-1979, 1941-1979 (Box-folder 5/23)
- SERIES XI: OFFICE FILES, 1951-1992 (Box-folder 2/11-2/12; 2/17; 4/28-4/31; 5/8; 6/40-6/44)
  Series XI contains various files pertaining to the day-to-day workings of the WSA.
  The series is subdivided by material format: Subseries A: Constitutions and By-Laws; Subseries B: Wage Scale for Plumbers and Steamfitters; Subseries C: List of Local Unions, pre-1970; Subseries D: William "Bill" Ford, Journeyman and Apprentice Coordinator's Reports; Subseries E: Plumbers and Pipefitters Council of the Northwest; Subseries F: Letters re: Illness and Death of William J. Linaham; Subseries G: Concrete Cutting/Concrete Coring. Individual files within Subseries A: Constitutions and By-Laws are arranged in reverse chronological order.
  - Subseries A: Constitutions and By-Laws, 1951-1992 (Box-folder 6/40-6/44)
    - WSA Constitution and By-Laws, 1992 (Box-folder 6//40)
    - WSA Constitution and By-Laws, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 6/41)
    - WSA Constitution and By-Laws, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 6/42)
    - WSA Constitution and By-Laws, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 6/43)
    - WSA Constitution and By-Laws, 1951-1959 (Box-folder 6/44)
  - Subseries B: Wage Scale for Plumbers and Steamfitters, 1946-1982 (Box-folder 2/11)
  - Subseries C: List of Local Unions, pre-1970, Undated (Box-folder 2/12)
  - Subseries D: William "Bill" Ford, Journeyman and Apprentice Coordinator's Reports, 1971-1980 (Box-folder 4/28)
  - Subseries E: Plumbers and Pipefitters Council of the Northwest, 1973-1979 (Box-folder 4/29)
  - Subseries F: Letters re: Illness and Death of William J. Linaham, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 2/17)
  - Subseries G: Concrete Cutting/Concrete Coring Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 5/8)
  - Subseries H: Affidavits of Noncommunist Union Officers, 1954 (Box-folder 4/30)
  - Subseries I: Plumbers Licensing Act, circa 1960-1979 (Box-folder 4/31)
- SERIES XII: WSA CONVENTIONS AND RESOLUTIONS, 1946-1992 (Box-folder 5/31-5/44; 6/1-6/39; 6/45-6/51)
  Series XII contains extensive minutes, correspondence and other materials pertaining to the annual WSA conventions from 1946-1992, as well as some of the resolutions that evolved out of the conventions during the 1960s-1970s.
  The series is subdivided by material format: Subseries A: WSA Conventions; Subseries B: WSA Resolutions. The individual files within Subseries A: WSA Conventions are arranged in reverse chronological order by the year that the convention was held. The files in Subseries B: WSA Resolutions are arranged in reverse chronological order.
  - Subseries A: WSA Conventions, 1946-1992 (Box-folder 5/31-5/44; 6/1-6/39)
    - WSA 1992 Convention in Pasco (Box-folder 6/8)
    - WSA 1990 Convention in Semiahmoo (Box-folder 6/7)
    - WSA 64th Convention in Pasco - 1989 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - WSA 63rd Convention in Blaine - 1987, 1987/1988 (Box-folder 6/5)
    - WSA 62nd Convention in Wenatchee - 1986 (Box-folder 6/4)
    - WSA 61st Convention in Richland - 1985, Part 1/2 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - WSA 61st Convention in Richland - 1985, Part 2/2 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - WSA 60th Convention in Olympia - 1984 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - WSA 59th Convention in Spokane - 1983 (Box-folder 5/44)
    - WSA 58th Convention in Ocean Shores -1982 (Box-folder 5/43)
    - WSA 57th Convention in Everett - 1981 (Box-folder 5/42)
    - WSA 56th Annual Convention in Spokane - 1980, Part 1/2 (Box-folder 5/40)
    - WSA 56th Annual Convention in Spokane - 1980, Part 2/2 (Box-folder 5/41)
    - WSA 55th Annual Convention in Kelso - 1977 (Box-folder 5/39)
    - WSA 54th Annual Convention in Seattle - 1975, Part 1/2, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 5/37)
    - WSA 54th Annual Convention in Seattle - 1975, Part 2/2, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 5/38)
    - Minutes of the WSA 54th Annual Convention in Seattle, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 6/9)
    - WSA 53rd Annual Convention in Spokane -1974, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 5/36)
    - Minutes of the WSA 53rd Annual Convention in Spokane, 1974 (Box-folder 6/10)
    - WSA 52nd Annual Convention in Pasco - 1973, Part 1/2, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 5/34)
    - WSA 52nd Annual Convention in Pasco -1973, Part 2/2, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 5/35)
    - Minutes of the WSA 52nd Annual Convention in Pasco, 1973 (Box-folder 6/11)
    - WSA 51st Annual Convention in Spokane - 1972, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 5/33)
    - Minutes of the WSA 51st Annual Convention in Olympia, 1972 (Box-folder 6/12)
    - WSA 50th "Golden Anniversary" Annual Convention in Yakima - 1971, Part 1/2, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 5/31)
    - WSA 50th "Golden Anniversary" Annual Convention in Yakima - 1971, Part 2/2, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 5/32)
    - Minutes of the WSA 50th Annual Convention in Yakima, 1971 (Box-folder 6/13)
    - WSA 49th Annual Convention in Bellingham - 1970, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 5/30)
    - Minutes of the WSA 49th Annual Convention in Bellingham, 1970 (Box-folder 6/14)
    - Minutes of the WSA 48th Annual Convention in Spokane, 1969 (Box-folder 6/15)
    - Minutes of the WSA 47th Annual Convention in Seattle, 1968 (Box-folder 6/16)
    - WSA 47th Annual Convention in Seattle - 1968, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 6/17)
    - Minutes of the WSA 46th Annual Convention in Kennewick, 1967 (Box-folder 6/18)
    - Minutes of the WSA 45th Annual Convention in Tacoma, 1966 (Box-folder 6/19)
    - Minutes of the WSA 44th Annual Convention in Yakima, 1965 (Box-folder 6/20)
    - Minutes of the WSA 43rd Annual Convention in Bellingham, 1964 (Box-folder 6/21)
    - Minutes of the WSA 42nd Annual Convention in Spokane, 1963 (Box-folder 6/22)
    - Minutes of the WSA 41st Annual Convention in Seattle, 1962 (Box-folder 6/23)
    - Minutes of the WSA 40th Annual Convention in Kennewick, 1961 (Box-folder 6/24)
    - Minutes of the WSA 39th Annual Convention in Yakima, 1960 (Box-folder 6/25)
    - Minutes of the WSA 38th Annual Convention in Bellingham, 1959 (Box-folder 6/26)
    - Minutes of the WSA 37th Annual Convention in Spokane, 1958 (Box-folder 6/27)
    - Minutes of the WSA 36th Annual Convention in Kennewick, 1957 (Box-folder 6/28)
    - Minutes of the WSA 35th Annual Convention in Seattle, 1956 (Box-folder 6/29)
    - Minutes of the WSA 34th Annual Convention in Tacoma, 1955 (Box-folder 6/30)
    - Minutes of the WSA 33rd Annual Convention in Bellingham, 1954 (Box-folder 6/31)
    - Minutes of the WSA 32nd Annual Convention in Spokane, 1953 (Box-folder 6/32)
    - Minutes of the WSA 31st Annual Convention in Seattle, 1952 (Box-folder 6/33)
    - Minutes of the WSA 30th Annual Convention in Bremerton, 1951 (Box-folder 6/34)
    - Minutes of the WSA 29th Annual Convention, 1950 (Box-folder 6/35)
    - Minutes of the WSA 28th Annual Convention in Tacoma, 1949 (Box-folder 6/36)
    - Minutes of the WSA 27th Annual Convention in Walla Walla, 1948 (Box-folder 6/37)
    - Minutes of the WSA 26th Annual Convention in Kelso, 1947 (Box-folder 6/38)
    - Minutes of the WSA 25th Annual Convention in Bellingham, 1946 (Box-folder 6/39)
  - Subseries B: WSA Resolutions, 1960-1974 (Box-folder 6/45-6/51)
    - Resolutions, 1974 (Box-folder 6/45)
    - Resolutions, Part 1/3, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 6/46)
    - Resolutions, Part 2/3, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 6/47)
    - Resolutions, Part 3/3, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 6/48)
    - Resolutions, 1969 (Box-folder 6/49)
    - Resolutions, 1968 (Box-folder 6/50)
    - Resolutions, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 6/51)
- SERIES XIII: WSA LOCALS, 1955-1972 (Box-folder 1/26-1/29)
  Series XII contains meeting minutes created by individual locals within the WSA. These files were obtained by the WSA post-production.
  The series is subdivided by creator: Subseries A: Meeting Minutes of Local 40 (Tacoma) and Subseries B: Meeting Minutes of Local 358 (Aberdeen). Individual files within Subseries A: Records of Local 40 (Tacoma) are arranged in reverse chronological order.
  - Subseries A: Meeting Minutes of Local 40 (Tacoma), 1955-1958 (Box-folder 1/26-1/28)
    - Minutes of the Regular Meetings of Local #40, 1958 (Box-folder 1/26)
    - Minutes of the Regular Meetings of Local #40, 1957 (Box-folder 1/27)
    - Minutes of the Regular Meetings of Local #40, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 1/28)
  - Subseries B: Meeting Minutes of Local 358 (Aberdeen), 1968-1972 (Box-folder 1/29)